[{"id": "59049e7ecf93664eb10486b4", "question": "What country does the rock band \"Enter Shikari\" originate from?", "answer": "England", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389fa", "question": "What is Jack Dawkins' nickname in \"Oliver Twist\"?", "answer": "The Artful Dodger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef93fe6ce05a3942286e93", "question": "What show did \"TV Guide\" name the \"best TV show of all time\" in 2002?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c53f0775fa611bce67c5", "question": "What part of a building do trusses support?", "answer": "Roof", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a73a6c0f9723ab15cb5c", "question": "What US state has the highest number of electoral votes?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d4", "question": "Cher won an Oscar for her role in what film?", "answer": "Moonstruck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943c", "question": "The 1987 movie \"Full Metal Jacket\" was filmed in which country?", "answer": "England", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dff", "question": "Whose tombstone bears the inscription \"That's All Folks\"?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe5250d1bf59ab7d2e380f1", "question": "Where did the word \"hamburger\" first appear in the US?", "answer": "In a Walla Walla newspaper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c8749076251badbead6", "question": "What was the first country to put a woman in space?", "answer": "The Soviet Union -- In 1963, cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova\u00a0orbited the Earth 48 times in a space capsule named Vostok 6.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba23", "question": "What is the maximum possible break in snooker?", "answer": "147", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a5", "question": "What is the Latin word for poison?", "answer": "Virus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff6686852a821ff76ae8b04", "question": "Who are the first people known to have consumed chocolate?", "answer": "There is evidence that the ancient Olmecs of what is now Mexico consumed chocolate beverages as far back as 1900 BC.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d2", "question": "In which comic book did Batman make his first appearance?", "answer": "Detective Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc80", "question": "What Converse salesman is the only person in both the Basketball Hall of Fame and the Sporting Goods Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Chuck Taylor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de6", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"orangutan\"?", "answer": "Malay", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd809e347d002c297e4c6", "question": "In Greek mythology, who flew too close to the Sun?", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf58", "question": "What do the letters A and W stand for in the \"A&W\" root beer name?", "answer": "Allen and Wright", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae70", "question": "What US first lady was nicknamed \"the Silver Fox\"?", "answer": "Barbara Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc5", "question": "Ditra Flame was the \"Lady in Black\" who took thirteen red roses to what actor's grave every year?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f1", "question": "In which 1984 film did Ralph Macchio and Elisabeth Shue star in?", "answer": "The Karate Kid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596761662b59efe0e9417ea3", "question": "What country music artist was nicknamed \"Chief\" after his maternal grandfather, who was Chief of Police?", "answer": "Eric Church", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a63c32ebb971c1417fb9c", "question": "The film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\", was released in what year?", "answer": "1991", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339455", "question": "What musical starred Vanessa Redgrave as Guinevere?", "answer": "Camelot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a41b", "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Dacia?", "answer": "Romania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a369", "question": "What is the capital of Monaco?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e83", "question": "What future game show host had a Top Forty hit with 1968's \"Naturally Stoned\"?", "answer": "Chuck Woolery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea7", "question": "What flower symbolizes the throne of the Japanese emperor?", "answer": "The chrysanthemum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b290", "question": "Who was the first US president to die in office?", "answer": "William Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25eed16682715b82711cd1", "question": "Which European country strted colonizing Venezuela in 1522?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db6", "question": "Whose tombstone, in Siler City, North Carolina, bears the inscription \"Aunt Bee\"?", "answer": "Frances Bavier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af3c", "question": "What plan was developed by General Winfield Scott to defeat the Confederate Army?", "answer": "Anaconda Plan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600242794be4723ccac22186", "question": "Atticus Finch is the name of the narrator\u2019s father in which classic 1960 novel?", "answer": "\"To Kill a Mockingbird\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba5c", "question": "What kind of fish is lox made from?", "answer": "Salmon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c2c", "question": "Created by Al Capp, what comic strip appeared in newspapers from 1934 until 1977?", "answer": "Li'l Abner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590089fbcf842fa4c4ba968e", "question": "Which band recorded the album titled \"Slippery When Wet\"?", "answer": "Bon Jovi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef96b46ce05a3942286e9f", "question": "Who was the first sitting US President to throw the first pitch on Opening Day?", "answer": "William Howard Taft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ae", "question": "What number of Downing Street serves as the residence for the Prime Minister of the UK?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24c", "question": "What is considered the fifth sense?", "answer": "Touch", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca86", "question": "What culinary ingredient did Hippolyte M\u00e8ge-Mouri\u00e8s invent?", "answer": "Margarine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbd", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Raccoons\" fraternity?", "answer": "The Honeymooners", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b082", "question": "What famous woman became known as \"The Lady with the Lamp\" during the Crimean War?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c8dc877e98cb977789ed", "question": "Which US state is home to Olympic National Park?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66029a5bfecdd737e0831", "question": "What percentage of Americans believe in Astrology", "answer": "26", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacf", "question": "What is the second largest state in the US?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596760912b59efe0e9417e9d", "question": "A baby oyster is called a what?", "answer": "A spat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ba", "question": "What \"Twilight Zone\" writer also created \"The New People\" in 1969?", "answer": "Rod Serling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41b", "question": "What is the common word for a weight suspended from a pivot that can move freely?", "answer": "A pendulum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6bb", "question": "What river is located along the southern border of Texas?", "answer": "Rio Grande River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339494", "question": "In which US state does the movie \"Night of the Living Dead\" take place?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa9", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Wild Palms\"?", "answer": "William Faulkner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a16d", "question": "Which Alan Parker film dealt with racial murders in America?", "answer": "Mississippi Burning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc2", "question": "In what year was David Bowie inducted into The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ec", "question": "Which TV production company brought the show \"Late Night With David Letterman\" to NBC?", "answer": "Worldwide Pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b1be01dd7bf43be5e794", "question": "Which best describes an idea that\u2019s \"all sizzle and no steak\"?", "answer": "Not living up to expectations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab26", "question": "What separates Madagascar from Mozambique?", "answer": "Mozambique Channel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950f", "question": "Who voiced the character Atta in the movie \"A Bug's Life\"?", "answer": "Julia Louis Dreyfuss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa5", "question": "With what is charcoal and saltpeter mixed to make gunpowder?", "answer": "Sulfur", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c720", "question": "What part of the human body experiences different growth rates called anagen, catagen, and telogen?", "answer": "The hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba1", "question": "What is the name for the fingers of a fork?", "answer": "Tines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f7", "question": "Approximately how many acres is a baseball field?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f5644233a95c66dc4fe74c", "question": "What was the name of Eddie Murphy's character in the 1984 film \"Beverly Hills Cop\"?", "answer": "Axel Foley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b5a0e662d71a53650ffd", "question": "How did Jay Gatsby make his money in \"The Great Gatsby\"?", "answer": "Bootlegging", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a89d", "question": "In what modern day country was Dalmatia located?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06f", "question": "Tin or aluminum is the traditional gift for which anniversary?", "answer": "Tenth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc7df6de0eb824d4052fa", "question": "What island changes hands between France and Spain every six months?", "answer": "Pheasant Island -- The two-acre island lies in the Bidasoa River between France and Spain.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b7", "question": "What did cowboys refer to as \"tonsil paint\"?", "answer": "Whisky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4a", "question": "In the movie \"The Matrix\", what colored pill does Neo take?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4f", "question": "What country music artist was married briefly to actress Renee Zellweger?", "answer": "Kenny Chesney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c4b5fbde8045e48466a0", "question": "What does the African dung beetle use to navigate at night?", "answer": "The Milky Way -- The only animal known to navigate using the Milky Way, they can move objects that are 50 times their weight.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddc", "question": "Who played the Dark Knight in the movie \"Batman Forever\"?", "answer": "Val Kilmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e38d479f6c8a670a7957c5b", "question": "When a nose is said to be \"Retrousse\", what does it mean?", "answer": "It turns upward", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d47103f8e329de4f877897", "question": "What is the brewery featured in the British soap opera \"Coronation Street\"?", "answer": "Newton and Ridley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8a", "question": "What type of artwork depicts human characteristics that are modified or exaggerated in a humorous fashion?", "answer": "A caricature", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bda", "question": "Mark Wahlberg has a tattoo of what popular musician on his left shoulder?", "answer": "Bob Marley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a218", "question": "Who won the first UK version of \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Craig Phillips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b07", "question": "What is the name of the Wally World mascot in \"National Lampoon's Vacation\"?", "answer": "Marty Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab9920b8cce1e6fda7055", "question": "What is the attempt to overthrow a government by force or at least interrupt its activities called?", "answer": "Sedition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af82", "question": "Who died three months into his 4th term as president?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9de08e748bb36357acde3", "question": "In what country is the grave of the famous German philosopher Immanuel Kant located?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b750", "question": "What game can you \"squidge\", \"squop\" and \"pot out\" in?", "answer": "Tiddlywinks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e6", "question": "Which missionary was the first European to discover Victoria Falls?", "answer": "David Livingstone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88e", "question": "What does the Kardashev scale measure?", "answer": "Energy available to alien civilizations", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afe", "question": "What 1995 Kevin Costner film was the most expensive movie ever made, until \"Titanic\" came along in 1997?", "answer": "Waterworld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a92120565ad31a57c7fd", "question": "What was the code name given for the first detonation of a nuclear device?", "answer": "Trinity", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015de83fe83fe1f2a824b6c", "question": "What actor was one of the most decorated American combat soldiers of World War II?", "answer": "Audie Murphy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923b", "question": "What is the nickname of Andy's prison buddy in \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927f", "question": "In seasons 12 and 13 of the TV show \"Big Brother\", what competitor is associated with \"crybernating\"?", "answer": "Rachel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4c", "question": "Who wrote the \"Man in the Iron Mask\"?", "answer": "Alexandre Dumas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e4", "question": "In what country was the \"Michelin Guide\" first published in 1900?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121bae63c99d48cd169b0f", "question": "An ailurophile is a lover of what?", "answer": "Cats -- \"Ailurophile\" comes from the Greek \"ailouros\", for cat, combined with \"-phile\", the suffix for love.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d40", "question": "What famous Dutch artist was born on July 15, 1606?", "answer": "Rembrandt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e8", "question": "What surname for John in \"The Importance of Being Earnest\" did Oscar Wilde take from the seaside town he vacationed at?", "answer": "Worthing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f3", "question": "Which famous Jazz club is the subject of a 1984 Francis Ford Coppola film?", "answer": "The Cotton Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20d", "question": "Which country were the 1920 Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a9", "question": "What is Goldfinger's first name?", "answer": "Auric", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc7", "question": "What is the capital of South Africa?", "answer": "Pretoria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffcfdfd9dc5ec6cd98a8327", "question": "Which of Shakespeare's plays features a sorcerer named Prospero?", "answer": "\"The Tempest\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cf", "question": "What country was policed by the Blackshirts for almost 25 years?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe656adae7e414034b5aecf", "question": "Which King of England was faced with the Peasants' Revolt in 1381?", "answer": "Richard II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febac6b7e83c707845b20ed", "question": "How many kilometers are in an astronomical unit?", "answer": "149.6 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93daf6bd93ce3a4e5f6b8", "question": "What astronomical model positioned the Sun near the center of the Universe?", "answer": "Copernican model", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75d", "question": "In the eye, what is the more common name for the condition also known as \"lens opacity\"?", "answer": "Cataract", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5901d831709c1c34536e6ea5", "question": "What is the protective coating called that covers chicken eggs when they're hatched?", "answer": "Bloom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba1d3874c93a3298b212c", "question": "How many distinct campaigns did the Crusades have?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a3", "question": "What mythological creature was the longtime mascot of Mobil gas?", "answer": "Pegasus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a13", "question": "What was Ralph Kramden's weekly salary as a bus driver on \"The Honeymooners\"?", "answer": "$62", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133890f", "question": "Who wrote \"Treasure Island\"?", "answer": "Robert Louis Stevenson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81b4fd0de9af39e9d4677", "question": "What president gave the longest inaugural speech?", "answer": "William Henry Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa3d", "question": "Where is the city of Tobruk located?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909cda7bb53d1af658864eb", "question": "What is Santa\u2019s postal code in Canada?", "answer": "H0H 0H0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941b", "question": "Radiohead took the title of their album Paranoid Android from what book series?", "answer": "Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c014", "question": "Which car company was founded by Sir William Lyons in 1922?", "answer": "Jaguar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae93a3574a5ce6b56b823e", "question": "In the fable \"The Tortoise and the Hare\", what animal judges the race?", "answer": "The Fox", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897b", "question": "In what book did Rudyard Kipling introduce readers to a mongoose named Rikki Tikki Tavi?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a067", "question": "What country is the band \"Men Without Hats\" originally from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b4b7e662d71a53650fef", "question": "What American city did Edgar Allen Poe consider to be his home?", "answer": "Baltimore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a7", "question": "What two actors exchanged faces in the 1997 movie \"Face/Off\"?", "answer": "Nicholas Cage and John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728c786bcd28c119383287", "question": "How many events are there in a heptathalon?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a4", "question": "The character Lieutenant Pinkerton appears in what work?", "answer": "Madama Butterfly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef944e6ce05a3942286e96", "question": "What was the first multi-camera TV sitcom?", "answer": "\"I Love Lucy\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010cb0d0775fa611bce6802", "question": "The last leader of the Soviet Union, Mikhail Gorbachev, was in what restaurant commercial?", "answer": "Pizza Hut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3c", "question": "What type of musical instrument is crafted with two parallel pipes, one known as a chanter and the other a drone?", "answer": "The bagpipe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe131b0e39efa6330e0fed8", "question": "Where is the Museum of Pop Culture?", "answer": "Seattle, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d03", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Barney Fife?", "answer": "Sheriff Andy Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe657eeae7e414034b5aee4", "question": "Which country did NATO bomb in 1999 to try to end the war in Kosovo?", "answer": "Serbia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b282", "question": "What US president was raised in a spa town called Hot Springs?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6d", "question": "Which author first became famous under the pseudonym Norman Bean?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b7", "question": "What name is given to twins who are joined together by some part of their anatomy?", "answer": "Siamese", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339115", "question": "Who wrote the 1896 novel \"The Island of Doctor Moreau\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b109", "question": "What city hosted the 1992 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b934", "question": "What color is the 3 ball in pool?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca45", "question": "In the human body where is your occiput?", "answer": "Back of the head", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c89efbde8045e48466de", "question": "What are names of the five layers of Earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "The atmosphere has five different layers: the troposphere, stratosphere, mesosphere, thermosphere, and exosphere.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc72", "question": "What year did the Parker Brothers publish the current version of the board game \"Monopoly\"?", "answer": "1935", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8b", "question": "Whose production company is \"Red Om Films\", named for her husband?", "answer": "Julia Roberts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94f", "question": "What caused fjords?", "answer": "Glaciers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ff", "question": "What was Cape Kennedy renamed to in 1973?", "answer": "Cape Canaveral", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9dd", "question": "Which US state is the Evergreen State?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600243894be4723ccac22198", "question": "What was the name of the first book in Laura Ingalls Wilder\u2019s \"Little House\" series?", "answer": "\"Little House in the Big Woods\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b753", "question": "Which company marketed the first digital camera, the DCS-100, in 1991?", "answer": "Kodak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d2", "question": "Nick Carter was a member of which boy band?", "answer": "Backstreet Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a81b", "question": "What is the better known name of the Spanish mission San Antonio de Valero?", "answer": "The Alamo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c766877e98cb977789cd", "question": "Where is Bohemian Switzerland National Park?", "answer": "Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f2", "question": "Since 1995 which state has led the U.S. in milk production?", "answer": "California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c8d4fbde8045e48466e1", "question": "Why do some plants send chemical signals to bugs?", "answer": "Signal for help -- Leafy tobacco plants send a chemical signal to wasps, who will seek out caterpillars eating the leaves.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7d06b877e98cb97778a61", "question": "Guadalcanal is located in what group of islands?", "answer": "The Solomon Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d128bb53d1af65886500", "question": "In the movie \"The Nightmare Before Christmas\", who wants to take over Christmas and orders the kidnapping of Santa Claus?", "answer": "Jack Skellington", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c0", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure of any animal?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071d5e3745b36be73039d7", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062a09c9d816e292245c12", "question": "Which German painter was best known for his depictions of naval warfare in World War I?", "answer": "Claus Bergen (1885-1964) developed a specialty of painting naval subjects, as well as fishing scenes and coastal views.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339089", "question": "Who beheaded Medusa?", "answer": "Perseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feb34337e83c707845b20c8", "question": "Russia is the world\u2019s largest country (by area), and its largest city (by population) is its capital. What\u2019s the next \u00adlargest country for which this is the case?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e7", "question": "Which US state is home to the world's largest naval base?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b044", "question": "How long did the American Revolutionary War last?", "answer": "8 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2df", "question": "Who received a chalet called \"the Eagle's Nest\" for his fiftieth birthday in 1939?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d18", "question": "What nationality was composer Ludwig van Beethoven?", "answer": "German", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3acbff048f679a45ab2e", "question": "Atoms of the same chemical element but with different atomic masses are known as what?", "answer": "Isotopes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf46", "question": "What is the full moon nearest the autumnal equinox called?", "answer": "Harvest moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc60", "question": "What material is denim made from?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c715", "question": "What vegetable gets its name from the Latin word for \"branch\"?", "answer": "Broccoli", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5989ac3acb8751d53e7d7609", "question": "In the gaming world, what does Mt. Gox stand for?", "answer": "Magic: The Gathering Online Exchange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc36e6ce05a3942286f23", "question": "In the film \"In the Heat of the Night\", who played the role of Officer Sam Wood?", "answer": "Warren Oates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e0", "question": "What decade witnessed the invention of the automatic bowling pinsetter?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8e6", "question": "What is the opposite of nocturnal?", "answer": "Diurnal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdab34a0b8cce1e6fda7044", "question": "What do you call filo pastry stuffed with chopped nuts and honey, or syrup?", "answer": "Baklava", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3f12d8b5801b8f54a7fbe", "question": "Which famous figures are featured on Prague\u2019s astronomical clock?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a899bb860d398dc9cf7a6a0", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the Pelican State?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae863cc7f28483af1e7fdcc", "question": "How many territories does India have?", "answer": "7", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c036", "question": "What are Limerick, Round Bend, Aberdeen and Octopus?", "answer": "Fishing hooks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339645", "question": "Where did Kevin's parents go for Christmas in the 1990 movie \"Home Alone\"?", "answer": "France", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4df0306d333868d34d71d", "question": "How old was Philo Farnsworth when he invented the television?", "answer": "21", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c6", "question": "Rene Laennac invented which aid for doctors in 1816?", "answer": "The stethoscope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c96", "question": "In Charles Dickens' \"Oliver Twist\", what is the name of the man who trains boys to steal for him?", "answer": "Fagin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3e", "question": "US President Woodrow Wilson was a member of what political party?", "answer": "Democratic Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062a19c9d816e292245c13", "question": "What Flemish Baroque painter is well known for his Counter-Reformation altarpieces?", "answer": "Peter Paul Rubens -- He was a proponent of an extravagant Baroque style that emphasized movement, colour, and sensuality.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb68b7e83c707845b2128", "question": "What color of star has the hottest surface temperature?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e3", "question": "When first published, what was the original intent of the \"Michelin Guide\"?", "answer": "To boost the demand for cars and tires", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb6", "question": "Who was the first African American to play in an NBA game?", "answer": "Earl Lloyd", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339868", "question": "In Disney's \"Dumbo\", what kind of animal is Dumbos only friend?", "answer": "A Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ec", "question": "What is the technical name of the pound sign?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9df61e748bb36357acde8", "question": "The City of Hot Coffee is in what US state?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbed", "question": "Jean Paul Gaultier was awarded what French title?", "answer": "Chevalier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76c3eeec85e375820b2ce", "question": "In which U.S. city was cream cheese invented?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26d", "question": "McLean Stevenson played which character in the TV series \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Lt. Colonel Henry Blake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab33", "question": "What New York City avenue divides the east side from the west side?", "answer": "Fifth", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf56", "question": "Which type of prepared bread is named after an opera singer?\u00a0", "answer": "Melba Toast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde4ed5c6c6b019850c9a87", "question": "Which U.S. president is honored in the wrestling hall of fame?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29e", "question": "What fraction pure is 18-carat gold?", "answer": "Three-quarters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8de", "question": "What animals teeth were used as knife blades by Natives?", "answer": "Beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdfbdd0003d27d341092bcb", "question": "What city's name means \"Lion City\"?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ad", "question": "How many wings does a butterfly have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c2", "question": "What is the highest peak in the Appalachian range?", "answer": "Mount Mitchell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062c20c9d816e292245c29", "question": "English artist Andy Brown created a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II using what?", "answer": "English artist Andy Brown created a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II out of 1000 used and unused tea bags.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a2", "question": "What character did Christopher Lloyd play in the movie \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit?", "answer": "Judge Doom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894d", "question": "What William Golding novel tells the story of a group of boys cast away on a desert island?", "answer": "Lord of the Flies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd7feec223966ae8f88da", "question": "Where was singer Billy Ocean born?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43c", "question": "What plastic often has its name shortened to PS?", "answer": "Polystyrene", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc84", "question": "The 2007 rule banning suspended NFL players from signing with the CFL was named for what player?", "answer": "Ricky Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a133", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl's brother?", "answer": "Castor Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d4702ff8e329de4f87788f", "question": "In electronics, what does the word modem stand for?", "answer": "Modulator-demodulator", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8e", "question": "Who played the role of Colonel Kurtz in the movie \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe9", "question": "Who directed his own father to Oscar gold in \"The Treasure of the Sierra Nevada\"?", "answer": "John Huston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad6d", "question": "What explorer was the first to sail around the southern tip of South America, and name it Cape Horn?", "answer": "William Schouten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f7475a9e54d890926f6f7", "question": "Buchaechum is a traditional Korean what?", "answer": "Fan dance", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c3", "question": "A shark's skeleton consists of what?", "answer": "Cartilage", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba56", "question": "What horse set a Kentucky Derby record in 1973?", "answer": "Secretariat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30c", "question": "Who played the role of Marcy Runkle on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Pamela Adlon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398fa", "question": "In what 1996 movie did Henry Winkler play the principal of Woodsboro High School?", "answer": "Scream", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac4d", "question": "What crop failure caused the Irish Famine?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ed", "question": "What member of Fleetwood Mac released a 1981 solo hit single titled \"Trouble\"?", "answer": "Lindsey Buckingham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c960", "question": "What name is given to a doctor who specializes in skin disorders?", "answer": "Dermatologist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b619", "question": "Who was the first female to be featured on the front of a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Mary Lou Retton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017349944491cbd7c5a1781", "question": "What is he maximum number of years a US president can serve in office?", "answer": "Ten years -- If he or she inherited the office after a president died or was removed with two years or less remaining in the term, he can serve two more full terms. Otherwise they are limited to one full term.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be91", "question": "Who hit .202 with three homers while playing outfield for the Birmingham Barons in 1994?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fd", "question": "What toe is the foot reflexology pressure point for the head?", "answer": "The big one", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c7a6877e98cb977789d4", "question": "Sutherland Falls is located in what country?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9b", "question": "In which year did the Japanese attack Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "1941", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b0e86c964118b2bb3809c5", "question": "In Slovenia, Saint Valentine is considered the saint of good health and the patron of whom?", "answer": "Beekeepers and pilgrims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b497", "question": "What year was the US an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6667552a821ff76ae8af7", "question": "What miracle is Saint Valentine said to have performed shortly before his death?", "answer": "According to legend, Valentine restored the sight of his own jailer's daughter.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf2", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Peter Pumpkinhead\"?", "answer": "XTC", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a0", "question": "In what state was the TV show \"B.J. and Bear\" set?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15d", "question": "Which city is served by Schwechat airport?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e9acaebfabb9c85d8a97f", "question": "Stilton cheese originates from which country?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358b175db0d66a186cb555", "question": "What is the name of the album for which Kendrick Lamar won the 2018 Pulitzer Prize for Music?", "answer": "\"DAMN.\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23f", "question": "What do peacocks mate with?", "answer": "Peahens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa45", "question": "What US state is known as \"The Magnolia State\"?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eea", "question": "Mr. Deeds hails from what fictional town?", "answer": "Mandrake Falls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c8b7877e98cb977789eb", "question": "Where is the Winchester Mystery House?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa7", "question": "Honshu is the largest island of which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21b", "question": "What city was Archduke Ferdinand killed in?", "answer": "Sarajevo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675c4d2b59efe0e9417e94", "question": "What was Vince Gill\u2019s last #1 as a solo recording artist?", "answer": "Tryin\u2019 To Get over You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea0", "question": "What chocolate cake is named for the Vienna hotel that keeps its recipe secret?", "answer": "Sachertorte", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c874fbde8045e48466d9", "question": "What is a word for a flock of ravens?", "answer": "Conspiracy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59220535a4edfd43a087ade8", "question": "How high is the center of the tennis court net?", "answer": "3 feet, or 91 centimetres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a56", "question": "What old TV puppet show was hosted by \"Buffalo\" Bob Smith?", "answer": "Howdy Doody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea5", "question": "What famous World War II general went into battle wearing two ivory-handled revolvers on his hips?", "answer": "General George Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600242814be4723ccac22187", "question": "In the novel by Cervantes, what is the name of the simple farmer who Don Quixote recruits to be his squire?", "answer": "Sancho Panza", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c364", "question": "What astrological chart takes its name from a Greek word meaning \"circle of little animals\"?", "answer": "Zodiac", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada3", "question": "Who was better known as Butch Cassidy?", "answer": "Robert Leroy Parker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe52de81bf59ab7d2e3810e", "question": "What is Ronald McDonald called in Japan?", "answer": "Donald McDonald", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3ec888b5801b8f54a7fad", "question": "Where in England was the Magna Carta signed in 1215?", "answer": "A Field Near Runnymede", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfde39dc5ec6cd98a8326", "question": "Which Stephen King novel takes place mostly in the fictional Overlook Hotel?", "answer": "\"The Shining\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5b", "question": "In 1995, Heather Whitestone became the first Miss America to have what disability?", "answer": "She was deaf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b5", "question": "To counter slipping sales, what was marketed, beginning in 1987, as \"the other white meat\"?", "answer": "Pork", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ec3dfe83fe1f2a824bfd", "question": "What artifact did Moses use to perform miracles and wonders in Egypt?", "answer": "A wooden staff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec5", "question": "Which Saint was murdered at Canterbury Cathedral in 1170?", "answer": "Thomas Beckett", "category": "history"}]